CÉSAR MOLTÓ MORILLA

GRAPHICS AND GAMEPLAY PROGRAMMER

ABOUT ME

I am a Spanish computer graphics and gameplay programmer specialized in real-time rendering and XR development, who loves researching and working with new technologies to help create even more inmersive and impressive video games.

I am passionate about technology, martial arts and travelling. In my spare time, I like to play video games, meet new people, watch movies and do outdoor sports.

SKILLS

GLSL / HLSL / OPENCL / CUDA / C / C++ / JAVA / JAVASCRIPT / C#

OPENGL / WEBGL / OPENCV / UNREAL ENGINE / UNITY

GRAPHICS PROGRAMMING / PBR / HAPTIC RENDERING / VR AND AR PROGRAMMING

GIT / MERCURIAL / GITHUB / PERFORCE

TEAM WORK / AGILE METHODS / PROJECT MANAGEMENT

LANGUAGES

SPANISH

Native Proficiency | Mother tongue

ENGLISH

Professional working proficiency | C1

GERMAN

Elementary Proficiency | A2

JAPANESE

Elementary Proficiency | JLPT N5

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

EMAIL

cmoltomorilla@gmail.com

WEBSITE

https://cesarmolto.github.io

PHONE NUMBER

+34620893530

LINKEDIN

César Moltó Morilla

EDUCATION

REY JUAN CARLOS UNIVERSITY

MADRID, SPAIN

Master in Computer Graphics, Games and Virtual Reality 2021 - Present

UNIVERSITY OF ALICANTE

ALICANTE, SPAIN

Multimedia Engineering Degree

2016 - 2021

• GPA: 7.90 / 10

ATHLONE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

IRELAND

Software Engineering Exchange Year (Erasmus K103)

2018 - 2019

• GPA: 8.93 / 10

WORK EXPERIENCE

HANDY GAMES

WÜRZBURG, GERMANY

Video game programmer

September 2020 - May 2021

- Was part of the team responsible for porting the game Titan Quest: Legendary Edition to the Android and IOS platforms.
- Implementation of game controller support, game rules, rendering of controller-specific graphics, UI elements and animations.
- Performed memory and rendering optimization, testing and troubleshooting for bugs and ensured correct documentation.

4FREAKSFICTION

ZARAGOZA, SPAIN

Video game programmer

October 2018 - September 2020

- Worked as a volunteer programmer on the development of several video game prototypes for pc and mobile platforms with Unity3D.
- Coordinated code remotely with other programmers to prototype and implement new game features; i.e., shader graphics, combat and interaction mechanics, player controls, enemy AI, etc...

PROJECTS

DODGEBALL MASTERS

Gaphics and Engine programmer, Project Manager

Programmed and supervised a dodgeball multiplayer game with 8 playable characters and +20 unique skills using OpenGL and C++.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/dodgeball-masters.html

BATTLE TANK

Solo project

Developed a head-to-head tank fight game with AI-controlled enemies, pathfinding, and an advanced control system in UE4.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/battle-tank.html

ROOM MAKER VR

Graphics and VR programmer, Designer and Project Manager

Led a 4 people team into creating a Virtual Reality scenario editor with VR hardware and the Unity 3D game engine.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/room-maker.html